EPISODE 4
（第 4 集）
Why won't Rang get up?
阿朗為什麼不起來？
Is he really sick? He went through nothing, no?
他真的病了嗎？也沒經歷什麼吧？
As far as I can tell, he's awake.
依我看，他已經醒了
He's just too ashamed to get up.
只是不好意思起來
So, he's pretending to be asleep?
原來是裝睡啊？
I'll get some ice water.
我去拿些冰水來
-All right. -That looks heavy.
-好的 -看起來很重啊
-It's fine. -Oh, dear.
-沒關係 -天哪
Thanks for your help. Go on.
謝謝妳幫忙，去吧
Hey, wake up. Hurry, come on!
醒醒，快起來！
Get up.
起來
Gosh, I even practiced lines for you.
天哪，我連對話都幫你想好了
-How about a rehearsal? -Shall we?
-預演一遍如何？ -來吧
What? She's a mermaid?
什麼？她是人魚？
How dare you bring seafood into our lineage of nine-tailed foxes!
你竟然敢把海鮮 混進我們九尾狐的血統？
There you go again. You always talk about lineage.
又來了，你動不動就講血統
Always on about becoming a mountain god, building a family legacy!
天天嘮叨著要當山神 傳承家族榮譽！
How dare you! You know I went through hell raising you!
你好大的膽子！ 我好不容易才把你養大的！
You bastard!
混蛋！
-How dare you rebel against me? -B-- Brother.
-你竟敢違抗我？ -哥哥
Can't you just let me be in love?
為什麼不能允許我談戀愛？
You brat. After all I've done for you!
臭小子，我為你付出了那麼多！
Geez! Both of you, get lost!
好了！你們兩個都滾出去！
-Get lost! -Okay, okay.
-滾出去！ -好啦
Bye.
再見
You're awake.
你醒啦
As you can see, I'm fine.
妳也看到了，我沒事
You still have a slight fever.
體溫還有點高
Don't touch me.
不要碰我
Why did you jump into the well?
妳當時為什麼要跳進井裡？
Because you were dying.
因為你快淹死了
I have unnecessary debt.
又欠了沒必要的債
This is when you say thank you.
現在該說謝謝才對
A fox must repay kindness, regardless of its will.
狐狸有恩必報，無論是否願意
Especially, when its life has been saved.
尤其是救命之恩
What do you want?
妳想要什麼？
Well, I…
我…
I want to fall in love.
我想談戀愛
That came out naturally enough.
說得夠自然了吧
Being a half-bood,
作為半人半魚
I was always rejected by both humans and demons.
我老是被人類和妖怪拒絕
But that ends now.
但這種局面馬上就要終結了
Finally, I can find true love.
我終於要找到真愛了
-Not in your right mind, huh? -It didn't work?
-妳是不是瘋了？ -沒有成功嗎？
-Do I look like a matchmaker? -He didn't even get my point.
-妳覺得我像是媒婆嗎？ -他根本沒聽懂我的意思
Just tell me who you want killed. I can easily blow up a village.
直接講出妳想殺的人 我可以輕輕鬆鬆搗毀整個村莊
That's all right.
不必了
Then, can you grant me a wish?
那你可以滿足我一個願望嗎？
-A wish? -Little ones.
-願望？ -小願望
Maybe about seven of them?
七個怎麼樣？
Are you crying?
你在哭嗎？
I was tossed into the year 1938 and worked my ass off.
我被丟到1938年，辛辛苦苦地工作
But for the first time, I'm actually glad I came here.
這是我第一次因為來到這裡而高興
I get to see a new side of Lord Lee Rang.
我看到了李朗大人的另一面
You're right.
是啊
I always hoped for Rang to go on normal dates,
我一直希望阿朗可以和女生正常交往
to build a family,
組建家庭
and to live a normal life.
過上正常的生活
The problem is that he's never dated anyone.
問題是他從沒和任何人交往過
Hell, he's a virgin who's never held a woman's hand.
拜託，他是個連女生的手 都沒有牽過的處男啊
-Do you have a plan? -Well, first of all,
-你有什麼計劃嗎？ -首先
we check their compatibility with their names.
先用姓名測試速配度吧
-Gosh, but it's all wrong. -This is science.
-算了吧，那一點都不準 -這是科學
My wife and I got 99 points.
我和我老婆有九十九分
Hey, but Ji-ah and I only scored 25.
但是我和智雅只有二十五分
Geez. This couple only scores 23 points!
天哪，他們這對只有二十三分！
See?
看吧？
Gosh.
天哪
I miss Ji-ah too.
我想念智雅了
Are you worried? Hyunuiong's probably kept her protected.
你在擔心嗎？ 懸衣翁應該一直在保護她吧
Before I came here, the forecast said it's monsoon season.
我來這裡之前，天氣預報說雨季到了
My Ji-ah always loses her umbrella.
我的智雅老是把傘弄丟
I hope she's not getting rained on.
希望她別淋雨才好
Cuckoo.
布穀
-Cuckoo. -There's a cuckoo here?
-布穀 -這裡有布穀鳥嗎？
It's a cuckoo I know.
是我認識的布穀鳥
Cuckoo.
布穀
-What are you doing up there? -Oh, my…
-你在上面做什麼？ -天哪…
Hello, my boss's brother.
你好，我們老大的哥哥
Must you leave the front gate hanging?
明明有正門為什麼不走啊？
"Bandits don't use the front gate!"
“土匪才不走正門！”
-That's what boss said-- -Just come down already.
-我們老大說的… -快點下來吧
So, did you look into it?
有去查過了嗎？
Here's the thing. I handed this out to all my guys.
是這樣的 我把這張畫像發給了所有兄弟
And?
然後呢？
There's this cultural mansion behind Joseon Bank.
朝鮮銀行後面有一家文化館
It's owned by a man named Park Ga, who's made a fortune from gold mining.
館主是一個名叫朴嘉 靠金礦致富的男人
Red-white mask robbed him?
紅白面具人搶了他？
Heard of Gyeongseong's seven gold mining royalty?
你有聽說京城七大金礦主嗎？
He only targets them and has robbed six of them already.
他專門盯著他們 目前已經打劫過其中六個了
What did he steal?
他搶走了什麼東西？
That's what I find strange.
說來奇怪
Cash, gold, and property deeds. All were left behind,
現金、金子和地契都沒丟
except the jewelry box.
獨獨少了珠寶盒
The jewelry box?
珠寶盒？
It's not here either.
也不在這裡
Sis!
姊姊！
Oh, my!
天哪！
-It's gold. -Gold.
-是金子 -金子
It's gold!
是金子！
This is Sunwoo Chan's house, also known as the "King of Gold."
這是人稱“金王”的鮮于昌的家
-And the owner? -On a business trip to Gyeonggi-do.
-主人呢？ -去京畿道出差了
Only his wife and daughter are home.
只有他的妻子和女兒在家
That's good. Go in and steal the jewelry box.
很好，進去把珠寶盒偷出來
Me? Come on. I've never stolen anything in my life.
我嗎？拜託 我這輩子從來沒有偷過東西
Then, shall I do it? A former mountain god?
難道要我去嗎？我可是前任山神耶
Let's say I go in there and steal the jewelry box.
我進去偷珠寶盒
You think that makes any sense?
你不覺得很奇怪嗎？
But I don't want to. Let's just stake out and catch the guy.
可是我不想去 我們守株待兔來抓住那個傢伙吧
We'll catch him and keep the goods. Now hurry and go.
我們既要抓住他 又要保住珠寶盒，快點進去
Stop mentioning your former post when you're at a disadvantage.
既然你現在處境堪憂 就不要再提以前的職務了
Nobody's looking. Just walk straight. Why that little--
明明沒有人，正常走路就好 為什麼要…
Wh-- What the? Geez. He's watched too many movies.
什麼？天哪，電影看多了吧
Put both hands over your head.
雙手舉過頭頂
Now turn around.
轉過身來
It's not what you think.
不是妳想的那樣
Honey! Yoo-ri!
老婆！宥莉！
You came here looking for me?
妳是來找我的嗎？
-Don't play any tricks. -That hurts.
-不要耍花招 -好痛
-I missed your violent nature. -What does this look like to you?
-我好懷念妳的暴力性格 -你以為我們是在做什麼？
Obviously, the beginning of our love.
當然是愛情起點的情景再現啊
When we first met, you were like--
我們第一次見面時，妳是這樣的
You threatened me with a gun, and even pecked me here.
拿著一把槍威脅我 甚至還在我臉上啄了一下
Yoo-ri, give me a hug.
宥莉，抱一下吧
You're not the first to break in here.
你不是第一個偷闖進來的人
You're the thirty-sixth.
是第三十六個
You're not Yoo-ri?
妳不是宥莉？
My name is Sunwoo Eun-ho.
我叫鮮于恩好
You should at least know the name of the woman who put a hole in you.
你至少應該知道 射傷你的女人叫什麼名字
Apologies, ma'am.
對不起，女士
Apologies? For what?
對不起？為什麼？
I'm not doing this because I want to either!
我也不想這樣做的！
Ouch! This really--
好痛！這真的…
Oh, my! W-- Wait!
天哪！等一下！
How can he run like that after getting shot?
明明中槍了，居然還能跑那麼快？
Hong-joo, it's a flower that only blooms in the boiling Fiery-Cauldron Hell.
紅朱，這是只盛開在火湯地獄的花
Goodness.
天哪
I feel warm already.
我已經感受到溫暖了
You're the best, old man.
老頭子，你最好了
Gosh. If you like warm things so much,
天哪，既然喜歡溫暖的東西
why do you keep punishing and tormenting yourself?
為什麼非要不停地 懲罰和折磨自己呢？
That's the only way I feel alive.
只有這樣，我才覺得自己還活著
Do you still have trouble sleeping?
妳現在還是睡不好嗎？
You dream about your siblings?
還會夢到手足們嗎？
My siblings…
即便在夢中…
They wait for me, even in my dreams.
他們也依然在等著我
I put raw rice in the mouths of my dead siblings, and incant this:
我會把生米放在死去的手足們口中 念念有詞地說著
"I never abandoned you."
“我從來沒有拋棄你們”
Even if I die soon, I want to tell them that.
即便我死到臨頭也要告訴他們這句話
But I'm always too late.
但我總是晚到一步
Even we, who are called gods, live grieving the loss of someone.
即便我們這些所謂的神 也生活在失去親人的悲痛中
I, too, lost my son.
我也失去了我的兒子
I was able to survive raising you guys.
是養育你們的責任幫我活下來的
Yeon, Moo-yeong, and you.
阿硯、無影和妳
Old man, if Yeon and Moo-yeong fought, whose side would you take?
老頭子，如果阿硯和無影打架 你會支持誰？
I'm not sure.
我也不知道
It's a tough question.
這個問題不好回答
I liked Yeon from the start.
我從一開始就喜歡阿硯
But I can't abandon Moo-yeong again.
但我不能再一次拋下無影
His bodily scars…
他身上的疤痕…
are all because of me.
都是因為我
They were good kids.
他們都曾經是好孩子
But why?
可是為什麼？
Both of them.
他們兩個
They're not the guys I used to know.
都不再是我熟悉的樣子了
Hey, hurry up.
快點
-A woman in there looks just like Yoo-ri. -Right, the reporter. I saw her too.
-那裡有個女人長得和宥莉一模一樣 -沒錯，那個記者，我也見過她
-Why didn't you tell me? -Who knew it'd be her house?
-為什麼不早點告訴我？ -誰知道那是她家啊？
-And red-white mask? -He's been following us.
-紅白面具人呢？ -他一直跟著我們
You're strong.
很有力氣嘛
Wow.
哇
Great balance too.
平衡感也不錯
But not so experienced at hand-to-hand combat.
但是肉搏戰的經驗不足
Shit.
可惡
Why? You have another talent?
怎樣？你還有其他能耐嗎？
Well, damn it.
該死
Let me see my stalker's face.
來看看這個跟蹤狂的真面目吧
A demon using an assassin weapon?
使用暗器的妖怪？
Rang!
阿朗！
You tried to kill me twice.
你曾經兩次想要我的命
My brother and I plan to go all out today.
今天，我們兄弟打算使出全力
Get him!
抓住他！
There's no path there anyway!
反正那也是死巷！
Boss!
老大！
Who are you people?
你們是什麼人？
With the gold he gave us,
他給我們的金子
I bought enough food for the whole village.
足夠我幫全村人買吃的
-Good for you. -They're human shields.
-那就好 -他們是人體盾牌
Who the hell is this prick? Is the suspense really necessary?
這個混蛋到底是誰？ 有必要這麼神祕嗎？
-Let's take off all their masks. -It's no use. He's already gone.
-摘掉他們所有人的面具吧 -沒用的，他已經跑了
What about the item?
那個東西呢？
It's yeot.
是韓式糖果
I'll come for it soon, Lee Yeon.
我很快會把它奪回來的，李硯
And this.
還有這個
This is a valuable original.
這是件值錢的真品
Even so, it's just jewelry.
但也只是普通珠寶而已
-What is that bastard looking for? -Hold on.
-那個混蛋究竟在找什麼？ -等一下
There's one last thing.
還有最後一樣東西
-Where are you pulling it out from? -My goodness.
-你把它塞在哪裡啊？ -天哪
-Geez. -Disgusting.
-好噁心
What is this?
這是什麼？
-What? Is this really the golden ruler? -Is it really?
-什麼？這真的是金尺嗎？ -是真的嗎？
GOLDEN RULER TREASURE OF HYEOKGEOSE OF SILLA
（金尺：新羅王赫居世的寶物）
-Is it something good? -Haven't you heard about the legend?
-這是什麼寶貝嗎？ -你沒聽過那個傳說嗎？
"He who beholds the golden ruler will revive the dead and make his name known."
“見金尺者 可使死者復生，名揚天下”
The item revives the dead
拿這件寶貝
when you measure the length and width of a corpse.
測量屍體的長度和寬度 就能讓屍體復生
Why would such a thing be here?
這樣的寶物怎麼會在這裡呢？
No one probably knew what it was used for.
也許沒人知道它的用途
There was a rumor before:
從前有個傳言
That the King of Silla's ruler was found in a gold mine up north.
說新羅王的尺 在北方一座金礦中現世了
I thought it was just a rumor.
我以為那只是傳言而已
A treasure that revives the dead?
可以使人起死復生的寶物？
Just who is he trying to revive?
他想復活誰呢？
Long time no see.
好久不見
Old hag.
老妖婆
Did I come too early?
我是不是來早了？
I wanted to watch you run amok some more.
我原本想看你繼續胡鬧的
But it's been a while since I saw you, so I thought I'd drop by.
但很久沒見到你了，所以決定來一趟
How about a cup of tea?
請我喝杯茶怎麼樣？
Who exactly are you, old hag?
老妖婆，妳究竟是誰？
Being raised by you, and almost dying, got me a bit confused.
妳親手養大我 又差點殺死我，真讓人想不通
Me? I'm a typical bureaucrat.
我嗎？我是典型的官僚主義者
I raised you three out of necessity, and removed you out of necessity.
我迫不得已養大你們三個 同樣也是迫不得已趕走你們
I like how simple it is for you.
只是這麼簡單真是太好了
Puts me at ease to do just about anything.
這樣一來 我做任何事情都可以安心了
I'm here to make you feel uneasy.
我這次來就是要你安不了心
There's only one reason I'm letting you be.
我放任你不管只有一個原因
You need answers.
妳需要答案
How did someone you turned to stone come back to life?
妳想知道 被妳變成石柱的人怎麼會活過來？
Who dares shake the boundary of the world of the Living and Dead?
是誰膽大包天 敢去撼動陰陽兩界的分界線？
Our Moo-yeong sure has changed.
我們無影果然變了
You dare challenge me with your eyes wide open too.
挑戰我的時候，眼睛都不眨一下
You're the one…
是妳…
who abandoned me.
拋棄我的
You're the one who decided to play the villain,
是你自己決定當壞人的
so you shouldn't look so hurt.
那就不該裝出一副受害者的樣子
Should you?
對吧？
That's why…
所以…
you needed a mask, huh?
你才需要戴面具，對不對？
Why did you come to this era?
你為什麼要來這個時代？
For what?
有什麼目的？
To bring my brother back,
我要復活我哥哥
and take back everything I lost from you and Lee Yeon.
還要把妳和李硯奪走的一切拿回來
If you wish to do bad things…
既然要做壞事…
eat well.
記得好好吃飯
It seems you're not fully recovered yet.
看來你還沒完全康復
You'll regret this.
妳會後悔的
You'll regret not killing me today.
妳會後悔今天沒有殺死我
Oh, goodness.
天哪
I dug into Lee Yeon's whereabouts as you requested.
我按照閣長的要求查過李硯的行蹤了
There is a strange witness in Gunsan.
群山有個奇怪的目擊者
Is that so?
是嗎？
Okay.
知道了
-You did well. -What if the old hag sees you?
-妳做得很好 -如果老妖婆看到你怎麼辦？
We've already met.
我們已經見過面了
Ta-da.
快看
Here. Have some tofu.
來，吃點豆腐吧
Gosh.
真是的
It still feels like a dream that you're by my side.
有妳陪在身邊，感覺還是像做夢一樣
Can I be honest?
想聽實話嗎？
I don't recognize you.
我已經認不出你了
You seem like the Moo-yeong I know.
你長得像我認識的無影
But I'm not so sure.
但我又不敢確定你就是他
What kind of person do you know me as?
妳認識的無影是什麼樣子？
You wanted to be a doctor instead of a mountain god.
你想成為醫生而不是山神
You cherished every single blade of grass.
你珍惜每一片草木
You got back up when you got hurt.
你受傷後總能重新站起來
But you cried your eyes out when Yeon or I got hurt.
但是我或阿硯受傷時，你會哭成淚人
What about now?
現在呢？
What am I like now?
現在的我是什麼樣子的？
I don't see you, even when you're so close.
即便你坐在我身邊，我也看不到你
I don't recognize you anymore.
我已經認不出你了
I shouldn't have become…
我真不應該…
a mountain god.
成為山神的
I should've just stayed by your side as Cheon Moo-yeong.
我應該以千無影的身份留在妳身邊
But your dreams eventually became mine.
但是妳的夢想最終變成了我的夢想
-Do you intend to kill Yeon? -What if I do?
-你是要殺死阿硯嗎？ -如果我說是呢？
Will you kill me?
妳會殺我嗎？
You guys have already drawn me into your dog fight.
你們已經把我捲入你們的混戰了
You know better than anyone, I'm not the type to sit back and watch.
你比任何人都清楚 我不是那種坐視不理的旁觀者
What the hell? You said it'll come back to life.
怎麼會這樣？ 不是說它可以起死復生嗎？
You call this the treasure of all time?
這也叫千古寶物嗎？
Maybe there's a manual.
也許有什麼使用手冊
The guardian stone is just a rock if it leaves its place.
守護石一旦離開它的位置 也只是一塊石頭而已
You're right.
有道理
This was how it all started.
一切都是從它開始的
The stone that creates a barrier,
製造分界線的石頭
and a treasure that awakens the dead.
和喚醒死者的寶物
What was he trying to do?
他究竟想做什麼？
The golden ruler was never spotted since the Japanese colonial era.
日治時期以來，金尺從來沒有現過世
It disappeared from the world after this period.
這個時代結束後，它就從世上消失了
That's why he traveled through time.
所以他才穿越時間，來到這個時代
Let's wait.
耐心等待吧
-What? -He'll come back for it.
-什麼？ -他會來搶金尺的
What's with the horse?
這匹馬是怎麼回事？
The mermaid asked for a ride.
人魚說要騎馬
Oh, my.
天哪
Aren't you going too fast for a first date?
第一次約會的進展也太快了吧？
She'll hug him from behind and say, "Baby, you're going too fast."
她會從後面抱住他說 “寶貝，你騎得太快了啦”
Don't worry. The traffic laws can't stop my passion.
放心吧，交通規則也擋不住我的熱情
Goodness. Your chest is so hot.
天哪，你的胸口好燙
Quit whispering!
不准再竊竊私語了！
I'll show you the bandit's passion. Clip-clop, clip-clop.
讓妳見識一下土匪的熱情，嗒嗒
-Should I kill him? -Let's run!
-要不要我殺了他？ -快跑！
Such a handsome horse. What's its name?
好漂亮的馬，牠叫什麼名字？
Oh, it's Lee Yeon.
李硯
Your brother's name?
這不是你哥哥的名字嗎？
Because he's a tough one.
因為他跟馬一樣倔強
But why a horse?
為什麼要我騎馬過來？
Since my legs are actually a tail, I can't walk or run for long.
我的腿是由尾巴變來的 沒辦法走路或跑步太久
It's always been my wish!
這是我一直以來的願望！
I've always wanted to ride a horse through the fields.
我一直都好想在田野間騎馬
If you want to enjoy speed, why don't we ride a car?
如果妳想追求速度 不如我們開車吧？
No. It has to be a horse.
不行，一定要是騎馬
YEO-HEE'S IMAGINATION
（汝熙想像的場景）
Physical contact is essential when riding horses.
身體接觸在騎馬過程中必不可少
The warmth you feel on your back will make a man's heart flutter.
背上感受到的溫暖會讓男人心跳加速
We will inevitably fall in love today.
我們今天絕對會墜入愛河
Put your center of gravity behind you.
重心放在後面
-I told you to maintain your posture. -Posture?
-我講過了，姿勢保持好 -姿勢？
-Align your head, shoulders, and butt! -Align--
-頭、肩膀和屁股在一條線上！ -一條線…
Don't provoke it with strange noises.
不要用奇怪的聲音激怒牠
Horses have sensitive ears.
馬的耳朵很靈敏的
Excuse me, but my legs hurt so much. My thighs won't stay still.
可是我的腿好痛 大腿會不自覺地顫抖
Now, imagine this.
想像一下
Say the enemy is coming for your head right now.
假如敵人從正前方衝過來了
Is this the time to talk?
妳還有空講話嗎？
Are we supposed to in battle?
我們是要去打仗嗎？
Don't be scared. Use more force.
不要怕，再用一點力
Put your center of gravity behind you.
重心放在後面
Giddyap!
駕！
Wow, you're quite talented.
哇，妳很有天賦喔
Really?
真的嗎？
Do you want to join our bandit gang? You'll make a good warrior.
要不要加入我們土匪幫？ 妳會是一名好戰士
A bandit gang…
土匪幫…
How could I lose them? Geez.
我怎麼會跟丟呢？真是的
Where on earth did they go to ride horses?
他們到底去哪裡騎馬了？
Do you intend to tail them every time they go on dates?
你打算跟蹤他們的每一次約會嗎？
I'm sure they'll be fine.
他們一定沒問題啦
We should host their wedding at a hotel, yeah?
我們應該在飯店幫他們舉行婚禮吧？
-What about a small wedding? -Nonsense. I want only what's best.
-小型婚禮怎麼樣？ -才不要，我要最好的
The venue, and everything else!
場地什麼的都要最好的！
We'll cast the best singers too!
還要邀請最好的歌手來獻唱！
-Let me be the host! -Sure, sure.
-讓我當主持人吧！ -好啊
What's that?
那是什麼？
Oh, dear.
天哪
-Baby! -It's alive.
-寶寶！ -是活的
Who would abandon such an adorable baby?
誰會遺棄這麼可愛的寶寶呢？
This blanket is made of the finest silk.
毯子是用上等絲綢製成的
So she's from a wealthy family.
她一定出身於富貴家庭
I know! She's the child of a mistress.
我知道了！她是小三的小孩
Maybe she was abandoned for being a girl, just like me.
也許是因為身為女孩才被遺棄吧 就像我一樣
Or the result of a Western-style love.
或者西式浪漫關係的結晶
It's trendy these days.
最近很流行的
Thank you for your opinions I could care less about.
謝謝妳們的意見 我一點都不在乎這件事
So what now? You girls gonna raise her?
現在怎麼辦？妳們可以撫養她嗎？
This is the gisaeng's home. We'll be in trouble if Madame finds out.
這裡是妓生的家 如果被閣長發現，我們會有麻煩的
You heard her. Put her back where we found her.
你聽到了吧？把她放回原處吧
-No. She's a foundling. -So what?
-不行，她是棄嬰 -所以呢？
It means "a child of good fortune."
意思是“幸運兒”
Foundlings bring good luck, so it's customary to bring them inside.
棄嬰會帶來好運 所以大家通常會把他們帶進門
You heard her. I'll take care of her until we find her parents.
你聽到了吧？我要照顧她 直到我們找到她的父母
Hey!
喂！
Want some?
你要嗎？
How is it?
好吃嗎？
Well, it's not bad.
還不錯
What kind of food do you like?
你喜歡吃什麼食物？
I'm not picky, but if I had to choose, I'd say naengmyeon.
我不挑食的 但是非要我選的話，那就是冷麵
What's your ideal type?
你的理想型是什麼樣子？
My type?
理想型？
I mean, what kind of person do you like?
我的意思是，你喜歡什麼樣的人？
That would be someone stronger than me.
比我更強大的人
Find a common ground, no matter what.
無論如何都要找到共同點
What are your hobbies?
你有什麼愛好嗎？
Nowadays, I'm into robbery.
最近喜歡搶劫
Why do you want to be a bandit?
為什麼想當土匪呢？
Because Yeon wouldn't approve of it.
因為阿硯不喜歡
You brothers are more complicated than it seems, huh?
看來你們兄弟二人的關係 沒有表面看起來那麼簡單
I've never even met my father.
我從來沒見過我父親
And my human mother called me a monster.
而我的人類母親喊我怪物
Lee Yeon was my only family.
李硯是我唯一的家人
Though he tossed me like trash, once he was seduced by a human.
雖然他被某個人類勾引後 把我當垃圾一樣扔掉了
At least you have family by your side.
至少你身邊還有家人
What about your parents?
妳的父母呢？
Why don't you go back to the sea? You can live as a mermaid.
妳為什麼不回大海？ 可以過人魚的生活啊
I like Gyeongseong and singing on stage.
我喜歡京城，也喜歡在臺上唱歌
I like the shining lights and the chattering voices--
我喜歡亮閃閃的燈和吵雜的講話聲…
Don't be mistaken.
別誤會了
There's no place for a half-demon
這個世界是容不下
on this Earth.
半人半妖的生物的
I'm off.
我要走了
I already have a lot on my plate with this one.
這個傢伙已經讓我很頭痛了
I hate human children.
我討厭人類小孩
-You liar. Soo-oh liked you the most! -Who the hell's Soo-oh?
-你撒謊，修悟最喜歡的就是你！ -修悟是誰？
Forget it. Just take it to the Baby Box.
算了，把她放回育嬰箱吧
There's nothing like that here.
這裡沒有那種東西
-Why don't we have our guys sell it? -Come on.
-不如吩咐我們的人賣掉她？ -拜託
I don't believe you two. You have no humanity at all!
你們兩個太過分了吧 一點人性都沒有！
-Are we human?
-我們是人嗎？
No, that's not food.
不能吃，那不是食物
I told you to stop lifting weights.
我早就勸你不要再舉重了嘛
Are you hungry? You want munchies?
餓不餓？想吃零食嗎？
Off you go. I'll go buy some baby formula and diapers.
給你，我去買一些嬰兒奶粉和尿布
Hey, let's go together. I have an urgent errand to run downtown.
我們一起去，我剛好有件急事要進城
You want to die?
你想死嗎？
I'll be right back. Let's get you some munchies.
我很快就回來了，我去幫妳買零食
Gosh.
真是的
Hey. Wh-- What should we do?
我們該拿她怎麼辦？
-Let's discreetly get rid of her. -We can't do that.
-小心翼翼地扔掉吧 -不行啦
What about casually losing her?
不小心丟掉總可以吧？
I'm sorry it turned out this way, but this is for your own good. Okay?
很抱歉是這個結果 但這也是為妳好，知道嗎？
Find nice parents and live a good life.
找對好父母，好好生活吧
Gosh, all right!
好啦，知道了！
These are snakeberries.
這是蛇莓
Hong-joo goes crazy for them.
紅朱最喜歡吃了
-Let's go. -Gosh, all right.
-走吧 -好啦，知道了
-Why is she here? -Did she come looking for us?
-她為什麼在這裡？ -是來找我們的嗎？
Wh-- She can't even walk yet! Which prick did this?
她還不會走路呢！是哪個混蛋幹的？
-Hurry, before Shin-ju gets back. -Hurry, hurry!
-快點，申炷就快回來了 -快點！
For goodness' sake!
我的天！
Have a good life, okay?
好好生活，知道嗎？
Shit.
可惡
Hey…
喂…
Hey, tell me. How do you keep coming back?
妳說，妳怎麼每次都會回來呢？
Is this even human?
這是人類嗎？
Isn't it a demon in disguise?
不是偽裝成人類的妖怪嗎？
Gosh. I don't believe this.
天哪，真不敢相信
Lee Yeon was an opium addict?
李硯以前會吸鴉片？
Yes, he was a huge fan.
是啊，煙癮超級大
Every demon in Gunsan knew of it.
群山每個妖怪都知道
-Ever seen him smoke it? -He doesn't even smoke cigarettes.
-你見過他吸鴉片嗎？ -他連香煙都不碰
-Did he quit suddenly? -No way.
-是不是突然戒掉了？ -不可能
Shin-ju stopped by recently, looking for more opium.
申炷最近剛來幫他找過鴉片
You were also victimized by Yeon, right?
妳也是李硯的受害者吧？
-I wouldn't say I was victimized-- -We recently formed
-算不上受害… -我們最近成立了
a Lee Yeon victims' club.
李硯受害者俱樂部
We meet three times a week.
每週聚會三次
VICTIMS' CLUB FOR DEMONS VICTIMIZED BY THE FOX
（受害者俱樂部 歡迎被那隻狐狸傷害的妖怪）
We offer therapy sessions and pumpkin juice for the swelling
我們提供心理治療，還為挨打的妖怪
to those who took a beating.
提供消腫的南瓜汁
He beat you?
他會打你們？
Yes.
對啊
Just because he didn't like her name, he beat us like this, and this--
就因為不喜歡她的名字 他就這樣打我們，這樣…
What's your name?
妳叫什麼名字？
-Bae Ah-eum. -Ah-eum.
-白峨音 -峨音
Lee Yeon's girlfriend's name?
李硯那個女朋友的名字？
Ah-eum, Ah-eum, Ah-eum!
峨音！
She hates that name the most.
閣長最討厭這個名字了
So? Where did you say you last saw him?
所以呢？你們剛才說 最後一次見到他是在哪裡？
Yeon got on a train to Manchuria?
阿硯登上了開往滿洲的列車？
Maybe he got off in Gyeongseong. It coincides with when he left Gunsan.
也許是在京城下車了 和他離開群山的時間一致
Jae-yoo.
載宇
Go get some opium.
你去找些鴉片來
What could it be?
這到底是什麼玩意？
The moles on her forehead…
她額頭上的痣
-It's the Big Dipper. -So?
-是北斗七星 -所以呢？
It's an asterism that controls death.
那是控制死亡的星座
But it also means to bring wealth.
但是也有生財的意思
Geez, something feels off.
天哪，感覺不對勁
She keeps coming back, no matter what we do.
不管我們怎麼做，她都會回來
Wh-- Why is it crying?
為什麼哭了？
I-- I don't know.
我不知道
Stop crying.
不要哭
You little brat. If you want something, just say so.
死小孩，想要什麼就講嘛
Geez. You think that will make her talk?
天哪，你這樣就能讓她開口講話嗎？
Okay. Hey, hey. Don't cry. I'll give this to you.
好了，不要哭了，給妳這個
Stop crying.
不要哭了
-Let's knock it out. -Oh, stop.
-打暈她好了 -別鬧啦
She'll die if you do. You have any opium or sleeping pills?
那會打死她的 你有鴉片或者助眠藥嗎？
It stopped.
不哭了
Just keep holding her.
繼續抱著她吧
Come here.
過來
Hey, it's damp.
濕濕的
-Gross. -She must've pooped.
-好噁心 -她一定是大便了
Hey, I'm a germophobe.
我有潔癖耶
-You're the ones who brought her. -It wasn't me.
-是你們把她撿回來的 -不是我
Let's make a bet. Loser raises her alone.
我們來打賭吧 輸掉的人要單獨承擔照顧她的責任
You only have two left, but I have four.
你只剩兩個了，我還有四個
-No! -Goodbye.
-不會吧！ -再見
-It's not over yet. -No, no!
-還沒有結束呢 -不要啊！
Oh, no!
不！
I'm giving you exactly 30 minutes.
我給你不多不少三十分鐘
Let me tell you something.
妳聽好
I hate humans the most in the world.
在這個世界上，我最討厭人類了
Especially, the pathetic ones who can't do anything on their own.
尤其是不能完全自理的可憐鬼
It's no use acting pitiful.
裝可憐也沒用啦
Don't cry, or I'll eat you up.
不准哭，不然我吃掉妳
What's so funny?
有什麼好笑的？
Are you laughing at me?
妳在嘲笑我嗎？
Wow, what a nice view.
哇，好美的景色
Why is it so quiet?
為什麼這麼安靜？
-How'd you put her to sleep? -Didn't take much.
-你怎麼把她哄睡著的？ -很簡單
-What's that? -It's nothing.
-那是什麼？ -沒什麼
-Why you-- -Nothing…
-你怎麼… -沒什麼…
How could you give her makgeolli? My goodness.
你竟然給她喝馬格利酒？天哪
Emergency! It's an emergency!
緊急狀況！
-What's all the fuss about? -Madame Ryu is back.
-大驚小怪地搞什麼？ -柳閣長回來了
-Who? Hong-joo? -She wants to see you.
-誰？紅朱嗎？ -她要見你
Lord Lee Rang, take the baby and hide! Go!
李朗大人，快帶著寶寶藏起來！
-Why? -If we get caught, we'll get kicked out!
-為什麼？ -如果被發現，我們會被趕出去的！
Gosh, just go.
天哪，去吧
-Lord Lee Rang. -Geez.
-李朗大人 -真是的
I think Madame Ryu's scarier than the red-white mask,
我覺得柳閣長比紅白面具人更可怕
so don't make her your enemy.
所以不要與她為敵
-Doing what? -Can't you just pretend to like her?
-怎樣才是與她為敵？ -你不能假裝喜歡她嗎？
-No. -Why not? It's just an act.
-不能 -為什麼？只是假裝嘛
Because I know her feelings are real.
因為我知道她的感情是真的
Even if I make her my enemy, I don't want to lie to her.
即便與她為敵，我也不想欺騙她
She's my friend.
她是我的朋友
Well, he can be so cool sometimes.
他有時真的太酷了
It stinks!
臭死了！
-You're here. -What's this? You smoke opium?
-你來了 -這是做什麼？妳在吸鴉片嗎？
I heard it's good money, so I might start selling.
聽說鴉片生意很賺錢，我也想賣呢
Are you a thug? Don't do it, even if it's big money.
妳是混帳嗎？再賺錢也不能賣
-I guess I'll smoke it then. -What? Have you lost your mind?
-那我還是自己吸吧 -什麼？妳瘋了嗎？
What if you get addicted?
萬一上癮怎麼辦？
His eyes are clear.
他的眼神清澈
And his hands are steady.
雙手穩健
He didn't even flinch at the smell.
聞到氣味也絲毫沒有退縮
So why did you call for me?
說吧，叫我來做什麼？
-I have a question. -Me too.
-我有個問題 -我也有
To be fair:
公平起見
Three questions each.
每人問三個問題
What if I can't give an answer?
如果我無法回答呢？
-We strip one layer at a time. -Oh, goodness.
-每次脫掉一層衣服 -天哪
First question.
第一個問題
Do you remember when we first met?
還記得我們第一次見面的情形嗎？
She's testing me.
她在試探我
That's what the opium was about?
吸鴉片也是這個目的嗎？
Does she know something?
她是不是知道什麼了？
How could I forget?
我怎麼會忘記呢？
You stabbed me as soon as you saw me.
妳一看到我就刺了我一刀
My turn.
該我了
Red-white mask. You met him, no?
紅白面具人，妳有見過吧？
-I did. -Where is he now?
-沒錯 -他在哪裡？
One question at a time.
一次只能問一個問題
My turn.
輪到我了
We swore to protect each other with our lives…
我們曾經發誓要冒死保護彼此…
And if we break it?
違背諾言的後果是什麼？
-We die by each other's hands. -Yeon…
-死在對方手裡 -阿硯…
I intend to keep that promise.
我會信守承諾的
-Why did you choose him over me? -I haven't made my decision yet.
-妳為什麼幫紅白面具人而不幫我？ -我還沒決定呢
Last question.
最後一個問題
What am I to you?
對你而言，我是什麼？
I can't give you the answer you want.
我講不出妳想聽的答案
I would never trick you
我永遠不會為了拉攏妳
to get you on my side.
而愚弄妳
Over my dead body.
除非我死
You just had to say one word. Even then and now, you're so uptight.
你只要講出那個詞就夠了 從過去到現在，你老是這麼拘謹
Who's behind the mask? He knows me, right?
紅白面具人是誰？他認識我對不對？
Perhaps, I know him too.
也許我也認識他
H-- Hey! Cut it out.
喂！別脫
The more layers, the prettier you look.
妳穿的衣服愈多，看起來愈漂亮
Oh, right. Take this.
對了，給妳這個
I don't know if you still like them.
不知道妳還喜不喜歡
I'm off, then.
那我走了
Hong-joo, what's wrong?
紅朱，怎麼了？
I got a letter from home.
我收到一封家書
My youngest brother is very sick.
我最小的弟弟病得很重
Then tell Taluipa and go home.
向奪衣婆請假回家吧
She said, if I leave this place, I won't ever become a mountain god.
她說如果我離開這裡 就永遠都當不成山神了
That evil old hag!
那個邪惡的老妖婆！
Hold on.
等一下
Here. Snakeberries.
拿著，這是蛇莓
They make sad thoughts go away.
可以趕走傷心的念頭
This is what snakes eat.
這是蛇吃的東西
So you have to pluck one eyelash before you eat one.
所以妳必須拔掉一根眼睫毛再吃
It purifies the poison.
這樣可以淨化毒素
What do you think? Am I right?
怎麼樣？我沒講錯吧？
Jae-yoo.
載宇
Yes, ma'am.
在
We're going to Manchuria. Pack your things.
我們去滿洲，收拾行李吧
On the count of three. One, two, three!
數到三，一、二、三！
JAMI GOLD MINE
（紫微金礦）
Mother's bawling her eyes out, Father. All her jewelry were stolen.
父親，母親的眼睛都哭腫了 她所有的珠寶都被偷走了
That's not important right now. We have another gold mine!
那都不重要，我們又有了一座金礦！
Put it on the front page.
寫在頭版上
I, Sunwoo Chan, may have been robbed thirty-six times,
我鮮于昌雖然被搶過三十六次
but I'm good as ever!
實力依然不減！
As you, the owner of the paper, use the press for personal reasons?
比如身為報社社長 卻拿媒體公器私用的實力嗎？
I'm also promoting the Governor-General's new gold production policies.
我也是在幫總督宣傳 新的黃金生產政策
It's all for the good of the country.
都是為了國家好
There's over 5,000 mines under development.
正在開發中的金礦有五千多座
Whether children or women, the whole country's nuts over gold mines.
無論兒童還是婦女 全國上下都在為金礦瘋狂
Look at this.
妳看這個
This is the era of gold bringing in money.
這是黃金生財的時代
Hello, Mr. Sunwoo Chan.
鮮于昌社長，您好
Miss.
小姐
I'm from Jongno Station.
我是從鐘路派出所來的
-What is this? -I heard an interesting rumor recently.
-什麼事？ -最近我有聽說一個有趣的傳聞
Unsan Gold Mine from Pyongan, Jiksan Gold Mine from Cheonan,
平安的雲山金礦，天安的稷山金礦
and Gahak Gold Mine from Gwangmyeong--
以及光明的駕鶴金礦…
I heard a man appeared wherever the gold mines did.
聽說哪裡有金礦 哪裡就有一個男人出現
-Who? -The Joseon people call him a fortune god.
-誰？ -朝鮮人稱他為財神
A fortune god?
財神？
He's an indigenous god that brings good fortune.
是帶來好運的本土神
You came all the way here because of some superstition?
你特地跑來這裡就是因為迷信嗎？
With all due respect,
恕我冒昧地問一下
have you seen a man wearing a bamboo hat with a Taoist Hermit's beard?
社長有沒有見過一個頭戴斗笠 留著仙人鬍鬚的男人？
I hear he munches on carrots, like a rabbit.
聽說他像兔子一樣 總是不停地吃紅蘿蔔
Father.
父親
C-- Catch that guy.
抓住那個人
-Get him! -Yes, sir.
-抓住他！ -是
Lord Lee Rang!
李朗大人！
Make a bet!
下注吧！
Which one will it be? Where could it be?
是哪個？會在哪裡呢？
-It's not there! -Damn it!
-沒有！ -該死！
-Damn, my money! My mo-- -Thank you, sirs.
-可惡，我的錢！我的… -謝謝各位
Boss!
老大！
Come here.
過來
Twelve months in a year, thirteen the past year,
一年十二個月，去年十三個月
365 days in a year. This doesn't come every day or month.
一年三百六十五天 這種機會不會天天月月出現
Don't be picky. Just pick one.
別挑了，請各位直接選吧
-You done reciting? -Number two!
-唸完了嗎？ -二號！
-Number two. -Okay, I'll bet.
-二號 -好，我下注
-Anyone else?
-還有誰？
Here we go. Will it be number one?
好了，會是一號嗎？
-What? You pick number three? -Oh, dear. It's not there.
-什麼？妳選三號？ -天哪，沒有
-The tiny brat's already gambling? -Which one will it be?
-這個死小孩已經開始賭博了？ -會是哪個呢？
-Oh, no. It's not two! -No!
-不是二號！ -不是！
-It's in number three. -Yes!
-是三號 -太好了！
-Gosh. -Thank you.
-天哪 -謝謝
Hey, hurry up. Next bet.
快點，下一局
One nyang becomes two,
一兩變二兩
two nyangs to four, four to eight,
二兩變四兩，四兩變八兩
eight nyangs to ten, then a hundred.
八兩變十兩，再變一百兩
Look here. Where could it be?
看這裡，會是哪個呢？
Here we go. Where is it?
好了，它在哪？
-It's over here. -No, number two.
-這裡 -不對，是二號
-I got it. -Number two.
-我知道 -二號
Number two.
二號
Number three again?
又是三號？
-I'm sure. -I told you so.
-我確定 -我就說嘛
Is it number two? Oh, dear. It's not!
是二號嗎？天哪，不是！
It's number three. Congratulations.
是三號，恭喜
-Take that, then. -That's strange.
-收下吧 -奇怪
-You're pretty good. -Here. Thank you, sir.
-妳很厲害嘛 -來，謝謝先生
Dongdaemun? Where will we go?
東大門？我們去哪裡？
Pick one, pick one.
挑啊挑啊
-Pick and choose one. -I won't fall for it again.
-挑選一個 -我不會再上當了
Do it again. Which one is it?
再來一次，選哪個？
-Number one? Okay. -Number three.
-一號嗎？好的 -三號
Okay, then. Let's go backwards this time.
好吧，這次我們倒著開
-It's not there. -What? Oh, no!
-沒有 -什麼？不會吧！
It's not here either.
這裡也沒有
-It's in number one, sir. -Wow, what are you?
-是一號 -天哪，妳是什麼東西？
Here you go. Thank you.
來，謝謝
Where'd it go? Where could it be?
去哪了？會在哪裡呢？
Number two?
二號？
-Number one. -Okay, number one.
-一號 -好的，一號
-I'll go with the baby! -Me too. Number two.
-我聽寶寶的！ -我也是，二號
-All right. -What does the baby know?
-好的 -這個寶寶懂什麼？
It's not in number one.
不是一號
Number two.
二號
It's in here. Congratulations.
在這裡，恭喜
Go away, kid. Go away, kid.
走開吧，小孩
Where will my hand go? Look carefully.
我的手會放在哪裡呢？看仔細
If you look close enough, your fate may change.
只要仔細看，或許可以轉運喔
Now, where is it? Where is it?
好了，在哪裡？
One more time.
再指一次
Number three?
三號？
Number three.
三號
I bet everything.
我押上所有的錢
Well, let's see.
打開看看
Number two.
二號
-It's not there! -It's number three!
-沒有！ -是三號！
Wow!
哇！
You really bring good luck.
妳果然能帶來好運
Lucky baby! Lucky baby!
幸運兒！
Fur, pearls, and expensive bananas. What is all this?
皮草、珍珠和超貴的香蕉 這都是些什麼啊？
I was in a good mood, so I splurged.
我心情好，所以大買特買了一波
-What happened downtown? -Nothing happened.
-城裡發生什麼事了？ -沒什麼
Why?
幹嘛？
Oh, sheesh.
哎呀
-What's all this? -I won it!
-這是怎麼回事？ -我贏來的！
-You gambled in front of a baby? -She's no joke. Let's keep her!
-你竟然當著寶寶面賭博？ -她很厲害的，我們留下她吧
Really?
真的嗎？
-You see this? -We'll raise you, baby.
-妳看這個 -寶寶，我們會把妳養大的
Gosh, my head hurts.
天哪，我的頭好痛
Goodness.
真是的
I wonder what's in Manchuria.
不知道滿洲有什麼
You said the man at Myoyeongak is Lee Yeon.
妳說過，妙緣閣那個男人是李硯
So what do you wish to check?
那妳還要確認什麼？
-That one's not an opium addict. -What do you mean?
-那個李硯不吸鴉片 -什麼意思？
I must see it with my own eyes.
我必須親眼看一看
The other nine-tailed fox who went to Manchuria.
去滿洲的另一隻九尾狐
Excuse me, ma'am.
閣長
Why do you like Lord Lee Yeon?
妳為什麼喜歡李硯大人？
I never got to play house as a kid.
我小時候從來沒玩過扮家家酒的遊戲
Because my life was a constant battle.
因為我的人生是一場持久戰
But when I'm with him, I feel comforted.
但在他身邊時，卻有種安心的感覺
It's strange.
很奇怪
He doesn't even know how to say kind words.
他明明連一句好話都不會講
CHEON HO-YEONG
（千虎影）
Brother.
哥哥
Have you been well?
最近好嗎？
Will Dad scold me?
爸爸會罵我嗎？
-So why did you run away? -I don't want to be a mountain god.
-那你為什麼跑掉？ -我不想當山神
You should be one.
應該是你去當才對
A child qualified to be one is chosen by Taluipa.
有資格當山神的小孩 是由奪衣婆挑選的
I don't like fighting and I find it scary.
我不喜歡打架，我覺得很可怕
I'm sure you'll become a great mountain god.
你一定會成為出色的山神
You're my little brother, after all.
畢竟你是我弟弟
Brother, tell me I'm on the right path.
哥哥，快告訴我，我的方向是正確的
Let me sleep.
我要睡覺
Why does she need a name?
她要名字做什麼？
Even abandoned pets have names.
連被遺棄的動物都有名字
Then what about Kim Du-han? He grew up to be strong.
那叫金斗漢怎麼樣？她長得很壯碩
Du-han? But she's a girl.
斗漢？她是女生耶
How about a hip name? She's from the streets, you know.
取一個時尚的名字如何？ 畢竟她是從街上撿來的
-What about Coco? -Coco! Wait--
-叫可可好嗎？ -可可！等一下…
Please be more sincere. Humans' fates depend on their names.
真心一點好不好？ 人類的命運是由名字決定的
Gumiho for nine-tailed?
叫九尾狐怎麼樣？
How about Lee Mi-ho, taking your family name?
用你的姓氏，叫李美好怎麼樣？
Lee Mi-ho?
李美好？
Hey, Lee Mi-ho.
李美好
-Don't touch me. -I think Mi-ho likes it too.
-別碰我 -看來美好也喜歡這個名字
Hey, Mi-ho!
美好！
Hey, Koo Shin-ju. Come here.
具申炷，你過來一下
What'll you do with her once time's up?
等我們必須離開時 你要拿她怎麼辦？
-You going to take her with you? -Oh, can I?
-帶回去嗎？ -可以嗎？
I know you can't even pass up a stray dog.
我知道你連流浪狗都會收留
But it's a completely different thing to take responsibility for a human.
但是為人類負責完全是另一回事
Do you hate Mi-ho that much?
你就這麼討厭美好嗎？
It's not that I hate her. You know I raised Rang.
我不是討厭她 你也知道，阿朗是我養大的
It's all my fault that he joined a bandit gang and that he died.
他加入土匪幫和死掉，都是我的錯
Because I failed to protect him.
因為我沒能保護他
But you did your best.
但是你已經盡力了
Find proper parents who can raise her, for her sake.
為了她好 還是幫她找對像樣的父母吧
We were able to catch him, but torture and blackmail won't work.
我們抓到他了 但酷刑和威脅都沒有用
He just eats carrots all day.
他整天只知道吃紅蘿蔔
And he's the fortune god of Joseon?
這個人就是朝鮮的財神嗎？
He's been sighted in gold mines all over the country.
全國各地的金礦都有他的蹤跡
Whether he's the fortune god or not, I'm sure he knows how to find gold.
無論他是不是財神 他一定知道尋找黃金的辦法
Do whatever you can to make him talk.
想盡一切辦法撬開他的嘴
For military expansion,
為了軍費開支
our priority is to secure the only international currency: gold.
我們的首要任務就是 取得唯一的國際貨幣，也就是黃金
Yes, sir.
是
Can we even use a man like him?
他這樣的人可以用嗎？
He is flaunting his useless power over those who are weaker than him.
他在比他弱小的人面前 炫耀他毫無價值的權力
Who better to use than him.
還有比他更好用的人嗎？
Any movement from Ginko?
銀子那邊有動靜嗎？
Though I am a little worried,
雖說我有點擔心
she hasn't gone anywhere other than the tennis court.
但是除了網球場，她什麼地方也沒去
She regularly goes to this boutique store.
她還會定期去一家洋品店
Is that so?
是嗎？
Look at the map properly!
認真看地圖！
Locate the gold if you want to get out alive!
想活著出去就把金礦圈出來！
What I do best, is sever tendons of someone like you.
我最擅長挑斷你這種人的手筋腳筋
-Must be hard work. -You bastard!
-一定很辛苦吧 -混蛋！
All right. Fine.
好吧
Tell me, tell me. What is it you want?
告訴我，你想要什麼？
Please find a baby for me.
拜託你幫我找一個嬰兒
-Excuse me. -What's wrong?
-等一下 -怎麼了？
-Stop that! -It's not her. Shit.
-別碰她！ -不是她，該死
Find her, quick!
找到她，快點！
-Yes, sir. -Scour the place!
-是 -全部搜一遍！
REWARD: ONE MILLION WON JONGNO POLICE STATION
（懸賞：一百萬朝鮮圓 鐘路派出所）
-Out of the way! -Out, out!
-讓開！
What is this?
這是什麼？
Is it an orphanage?
是育幼院嗎？
The Government-General runs the place. It's a facility for orphans.
那是總督府管理的地方 專門照顧孤兒
-I'm telling you not to send her. -All you do is gamble with her.
-我叫你不要把她送走的 -你只會帶她去賭錢
Mi-ho, how could I send you off?
美好，我怎麼捨得送妳走呢？
Is there a spectacle?
有好戲嗎？
Oh, that? Jongno Station is looking for a baby.
那個啊？鐘路派出所在找一個嬰兒
The reward is enough to buy a house.
獎金足夠買一棟房子了
If I catch her, I can turn my life around in one go!
如果我抓到她，這輩子就發達啦！
Wait a minute.
等一下
L-- Look.
看
-It's her! -I found the baby!
-是她！ -我找到那個嬰兒了！
-Lord Lee Yeon, go! -Over here!
-李硯大人，快跑！ -這邊！
Stop right there!
站住！
Get him!
抓住他！
-Shit! -Get 'em! Go, get him!
-該死！ -抓住他們！快去追他！
To the right! Turn right!
去右邊！右轉！
-Stop right there! -Stop, you bastards!
-站住！ -混蛋，給我站住！
-Come here, you-- -I got him!
-你給我過來… -我抓到他了！
Let go!
放手！
-Oh, no! -Hey!
-不！ -喂！
-Goodness gracious! -Oh, dear.
-我的天！ -天哪
Stop! Don't lose him!
站住！別讓他跑掉！
Catch him!
抓住他！
-How old is your baby? -I wouldn't know.
-你的寶寶多大了？ -我不清楚
-Right? -I think it's her.
-沒錯吧？ -應該是她
May I see the baby?
可以給我看看寶寶嗎？
-Why do you ask? -I think it's her.
-為什麼？ -應該是她
Get him!
抓住他！
Damn.
該死
-Get him! -Wait, damn you!
-抓住他！ -等一下，該死的！
-You're blocking the screen. -Move.
-你擋住畫面了 -讓開
-Go! Get him! -Hey, stop!
-快！抓住他！ -站住！
Hey, get out of the way.
讓開
Get him!
抓住他！
Get out of here!
讓開！
-Get out! -What?
-滾開！ -怎樣？
Have you never cried before, huh?
你們都沒哭過嗎？
Oh, I'm sorry.
對不起
You!
你站住！
Go, get him!
快，抓住他！
Shoot!
開槍！
You're okay.
沒事了
Here. Wait here a second.
來，在這裡等一下
I'll be right back. I won't be long.
我去去就回，一下就好
Get him!
抓住他！
I wanted to refrain from using violence for the baby, but damn it!
為了寶寶我本來不想用暴力的 但現在不管那麼多了！
Let go! You bastard!
放手！混蛋！
I'm sorry! Let me go! Let me go! I'm sorry!
對不起！放開我！對不起啦！
I'm sorry!
對不起！
How dare you shoot when a child's present?
你竟敢在小孩面前開槍？
-I'm sorry! -What the hell are you saying?
-對不起！ -你到底在講什麼？
How dare you bastards shoot at a child, huh?
你們這些混蛋 居然敢在小孩面前開槍？
Mi-ho!
美好！
Mi-ho.
美好
Mi-ho. Mi-ho?
美好？
Where's the basket?
籃子去哪了？
Oh, shit.
完蛋了
Mi-ho. Hey, Mi-ho!
美好！
Are they gone?
他們走了嗎？
Welcome.
歡迎光臨
You know who I am, right?
妳知道我是誰吧？
I'm here to buy some clothes.
我是來買衣服的
It's just my style.
剛好是我的風格
Put it on Lord Lee Yeon's tab.
請記在李硯大人的帳上
Oh, my-- Mi-ho. I'm sorry.
天哪，美好，對不起
It's my fault. I'm so sorry.
是我不好，真對不起
Gosh. She's burning up.
天哪，她發燒了
-Let's call a doctor. -No. I don't trust anyone.
-叫醫生來吧 -不行，我信不過任何人
You sure the gisaengs will keep quiet?
你確定這些妓生不會洩密嗎？
Yes.
確定
Mi-ho, why are you sick?
美好，妳怎麼病了？
Goodness.
天哪
Let's get the fever down.
先幫她退燒吧
Were you like this when I was sick?
我生病的時候，你也是這樣嗎？
You always fell ill when you were little. Do you know how troubled I was?
你小時候常常生病 現在知道我當年有多頭痛了吧？
I fed you everything that was good for you.
我餵你吃過所有補身體的好東西
Well, I don't remember.
我不記得了
This is why they say you get no credit for raising a kid.
所以人家才說養小孩沒好處嘛
Why did you take me in? You didn't even know you had a brother.
你為什麼收留我？ 你當時根本不知道你有一個弟弟的
Father told me.
父親告訴過我
What?
什麼？
When I was little, he left me with the old hag.
小時候，他把我丟給老妖婆
I never knew if he was alive or dead.
我本來一直不知道他是生是死
One day, he just showed up and said,
有一天，他突然出現說
"I forgot to tell you, but you might have a brother."
“我忘記告訴你了 你可能有一個弟弟”
-I'll kill him if I ever see him. -What a good son.
-如果我見到他，一定會殺了他 -好一個孝子
I'll help out.
我會幫你的
What was he like? Our so-called father.
我們所謂的父親是什麼樣的人？
I don't even know his face.
我連他的臉都沒見過
He'd use me as an archery target, feed me poisonous mushrooms,
他常常拿我當射箭的靶子 餵我吃毒蘑菇
and tie me to a rock to throw me in the river.
把我綁在石頭上，再把我丟進河裡
So you turning out this way is no coincidence.
原來你長成這樣是有原因的啊
Why isn't her fever going down?
她為什麼不退燒呢？
Hey. You're here.
妳來了
Mi-ho.
美好
Her fever went down.
她退燒了
Yeah, I'm so glad.
是啊，太好了
From now on, I'm in charge of raising Mi-ho.
從今以後，我來負責養育美好
You're doing a good job.
各位辛苦了
Make sure it's spotless, okay?
一定要一塵不染，知道嗎？
-Yes, sir. -Okay. Good work.
-是 -辛苦了
Great work, everyone.
各位辛苦了
Don't leave any traces of gambling.
賭錢的東西全部收走
Make sure there's not a single speck of dust.
務必做到一塵不染
-It's bad for her bronchial tubes, okay? -Yes, sir.
-不然會影響她的支氣管，知道嗎？ -是
What the? What's that smell?
什麼？這是什麼氣味？
Who the hell is smoking?
哪個混蛋在抽煙？
Give this to me.
給我
Put that cigarette out.
滅掉你的煙
-Hey, you! -No smoking. Starting today.
-喂！ -從今天起，禁止吸煙
-Why you-- -Only use nice words.
-為什麼… -說話要用好聽的字眼
-Is that baby lotion? -I'm not sure.
-那是嬰兒潤膚乳嗎？ -不知道
Check for parabens.
看一下有沒有防腐劑
Here.
來
-Hey, it's organic, right? -What's "organic"?
-是有機食品吧？ -“有機”是什麼？
Never mind.
算了
Mi-ho.
美好
Let's eat lunch when you're all done.
等妳塗好，我們就吃午飯
Put her down now. You'll spoil her.
放下吧，這樣會把她寵壞的
Attachment forms at this age. Don't question my infant care philosophy.
這個年齡段正是形成依戀的時候 不要質疑我的育嬰理念
How long should I recite this?
我要唸多久啊？
Until Mi-ho falls asleep.
唸到美好睡著為止
I'm going to send her to Seoul National University.
她可是要去讀首爾大學的
Geez, you're so dramatic.
天哪，太誇張了吧
You like this, don't you?
妳喜歡這樣對不對？
Look here.
看
Gosh, where did that shirt go? I'm certain I hid it here.
天哪，那件襯衫去哪了？ 我明明把它藏在這裡的
The codes are written on it.
上面寫了暗號
If it gets out, the whole organization will be compromised.
如果洩露出去，整個組織都會有危險
Exactly.
是啊
-What are you looking for? -Yeo-hee.
-在找什麼嗎？ -汝熙
Have you seen a floral shirt here?
妳有沒有看到 這裡有一件花卉圖案的襯衫？
It was sold yesterday.
昨天賣掉了
To who?
賣給誰了？
Where on earth can I buy baby powder?
到底哪裡有賣嬰兒爽身粉啊？
What in the--
到底…
Gosh. This is driving me crazy.
天哪，我要瘋了
Excuse me.
喂
-Me? -I had that shirt custom-made.
-叫我嗎？ -這件襯衫是我訂做的
It's mine.
這是我的
Name the price. I'll pay however much you want.
出個價吧，你要多少錢我都給
Apologies, but I won't sell.
對不起，不賣
Apologies, ma'am.
對不起，女士
You're him.
你是那個人
MANCHURIA
（滿洲）
Look what we have here.
看看這是誰
Wow!
哇！
Let's see. Seven moles on the forehead.
我看看，額頭上七顆痣
-It's her. -Who are you?
-是她沒錯 -你是誰？
I'm Detective Jung Dae-seung from Jongno Station.
我是鐘路派出所的鄭大勝警探
-So what? -Give me the baby.
-那又怎樣？ -把嬰兒交給我
What?
什麼？
Hurry up.
快點
Geez.
真是的
How typical.
真是經典招數
-Let them go. -The baby comes first.
-放她們走 -先把嬰兒交給我
-Please help us. -Then I have no choice.
-救救我們吧 -那我別無選擇了
Mi-ho.
美好啊
-Here. -Are you out of your mind?
-來 -你瘋了嗎？
Usually, the protagonists end up losing the baby like idiots.
通常來講 主人公最後都會像白痴一樣失去寶寶
-But we're no ordinary humans. -Who the hell are you guys?
-但我們不是普通人 -你們到底是誰？
Something like the Green Mother's Society.
有點像電視劇《綠色媽咪會》
-Anyway, you're all screwed today. -You crazy bastard.
-總之，你們今天完蛋了 -該死的瘋子
Watch your language in front of the baby.
不要在寶寶面前講髒話
You bastard.
混蛋
Oh? All right.
好了
Should I stomp him?
要我踩死他嗎？
Let's stomp.
一起踩吧
Take this!
看招！
Shoo--
呼…
What's this?
怎麼回事？
He reeks of blood.
好濃的血腥味
The governor's office offered a deal.
總督辦公室提出了一項協議
-If I don't bring the baby-- -Where is Hong-joo right now?
-如果我不交出那個嬰兒… -紅朱在哪裡？
I won't forgive you.
我不會原諒你的
The gold mines…
金礦…
I found gold!
我找到黃金了！
-If I bring the kidnapped Orchid… -Don't be scared.
-如果我把被綁架的蘭草帶來… -不要怕
…he'll tell me the baby's location.
…他會告訴我那個嬰兒的下落
Lee Yeon and I will fight to the death.
我和李硯會相戰到死
My dear friends are about to start a war.
我親愛的朋友們即將展開一場戰爭
Who are you?
你是誰？
It's me.
是我